# JUDE FIORILLO

PHONE (226) 989-7867 • E-MAIL JUDE.FIORILLO@GMAIL.COM • SIMPLEMARKETING.CA

January 22, 2019

Jonathan Suter Founder & President SimpleTax

Dear Jonathan,

I am writing to express my deep interest in the Digital Marketer role at SimpleTax. I am confident that I would make a strong addition to the team as someone who has digital marketing experience across four startups, and has 'done it all', from PR and SEO link building, to blog post writing, to social media and community management, search engine marketing, email marketing, and more. To demonstrate my genuine interest in this position, I created the website <a href="SimpleMarketing.ca">SimpleMarketing.ca</a>.

As the Marketing Programs Manager at Encircle, I currently oversee our lead generation strategy, using email campaigns, webinars, and blog posts to drive qualified leads through our sales funnel, resulting in \$80,000 in revenue opportunities. As the Marketing and Communications Manager at Velocity, I led the marketing team's strategic efforts to build awareness for Canada's leading startup incubator, including liaising with journalists to secure media coverage, crafting blog post stories to engage the startup community, and implementing event/program promotions. I implemented creative marketing initiatives that increased event participation by 20% to 5,000 participants/year. I also managed a marketing budget of \$100,000 and developed numerous marketing assets.

As a digital marketer at Sortable, I helped oversee the marketing campaigns of the company's seven fastest growing websites, which now generate over 5 million monthly users. I planned and executed unique, targeted product launch strategies, including Facebook and AdWords advertising, and created positive relationships with journalists at major media outlets, resulting in 200+ articles. I also worked with a team to support and engage a community of 150,000 social media fans.

I am not just a marketer. I have spent over 2,000 hours developing design and coding skills through work on personal projects, including the design and development of a user-friendly job search tool for tech workers in Canada (jobfairr.herokuapp.com, used 25,000+ times).

I believe in SimpleTax, having been a user for five years, and would love to build out its marketing strategy. I look forward to re-connecting and discussing this opportunity further with you.

Best regards,

Jude Fiorillo

# JUDE FIORILLO

PHONE (226) 989-7867 • E-MAIL JUDE.FIORILLO@GMAIL.COM • SIMPLEMARKETING.CA

## **EDUCATION & ACHIEVEMENTS**

### **BACHELOR OF COMMERCE (HONOURS)**

2003 - 07

QUEEN'S SCHOOL OF BUSINESS, QUEEN'S UNIVERSITY, KINGSTON, ON

## IMMERSIVE WEB DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM

2014

BITMAKER LABS, TORONTO, ON

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### MARKETING PROGRAMS MANAGER

2018 - PRESENT

ENCIRCLE, KITCHENER, ON

- Used HubSpot, Salesforce, and SalesLoft to drive qualified restoration contractor leads through the sales funnel.
- Wrote blog posts and hosted webinars to generate leads for Encircle's field documentation and productivity tools.
- Developed marketing assets and worked on 11 email campaigns, resulting in \$80,000 in revenue opportunities.

### MARKETING AND COMMUNICATIONS MANAGER

2015 - 18

VELOCITY, UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO, WATERLOO, ON

- Led the marketing team for Velocity, Canada's most impactful startup incubator, and home to 100+ startups.
- Responsible for building the Velocity brand, marketing and supporting events, developing relationships with
  partners and investors, mentoring startups on PR, writing blog posts and press releases, leading tours, and boothing.
- Implemented creative marketing initiatives to increase event attendance by 20% to 5,000/year across 50+ events.

FOUNDER 2015 – 18

JOBFAIRR.HEROKUAPP.COM, WATERLOO, ON

- Designed, developed, and marketed a job search tool in Ruby on Rails to help Canadians explore tech companies.
- Dedicated 750+ hours of work, while working full-time, creating a tool that has been used 25,000+ times.

# DIGITAL MARKETING MANAGER

2014

51MOMENTS, VANCOUVER, BC

Assisted with product development, and led the branding, planning, and launch of 51moments, an online
marketplace to hire a photographer, resulting in articles from local newspapers, tech, and family bloggers.

## SOCIAL MEDIA AND MARKETING SPECIALIST

2012 - 13

SORTABLE, REBELLION MEDIA, WATERLOO, ON

- Managed the web development and launch of our seven fastest growing websites (e.g. CPUBoss.com), generating 5 million monthly visitors. Applied mail, e-mail, and social media to promote websites, resulting in 200+ articles.
- Engaged 150,000 fans across 25+ communities by writing blog posts, producing media, and resolving problems.
- Analyzed 7M monthly traffic in Google Analytics, applied SEO tactics, managed SEM campaigns, and used CMS.

# 'MACROWIKINOMICS' BOOK RESEARCHER

2010

THE TAPSCOTT GROUP, TORONTO, ON

- Collaborated with authors Don Tapscott and Anthony Williams in the publication of the book Macrowikinomics, a Canadian bestseller and Financial Times Best Business Book finalist, which explores the topic of digital innovation.
- Conducted extensive research, fact-checking, editing, and writing for a 424 page book, and prepared CBC radio pitch.

RESEARCH ANALYST 2008 – 2009

MOXIE INSIGHT, MOXIE SOFTWARE, TORONTO, ON

- Conducted research, writing, conference planning, and executive support at a think tank led by Don Tapscott.
- Played a key role in the launch of a new digital marketing program and online collaboration platform.
- Actively managed a four month project to update the company's \$9 million research library of whitepapers on technology innovation under strict deadlines, including hiring, training, and coordinating an eight person team.

 $HEAD\ MANAGER \\ 2006-07$ 

NETIMPACT SUPPORT CENTRE, QUEEN'S SCHOOL OF BUSINESS, KINGSTON, ON

- Responsibly drafted and managed a balanced, twelve month budget of \$75,000 for a busy student technology centre.
- Trusted to independently oversee cash deposits, hiring, training, biweekly pay processing, scheduling, and supervision for a staff of 18. Increased revenues by 25% (highest in 15 years), while reducing expenses by 5%, by developing new innovative services and promotions, implementing centre renovations, and eliminating operational inefficiencies.

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS & INTERESTS

I am a creative thinker who loves technology, and I am proficient with Google Docs, Office Suite, Adobe Suite, HubSpot, Salesforce, Ruby on Rails, HTML/CSS/JS, and Google Analytics. I'm also well versed with SEO, SEM, and CMS systems.